geartrade.com 2002-08-02

# GearTrade - PRIVACY AND SECURITY

## Policies

**GEARTRADE PRIVACY STATEMENT**

At GearTrade we care about your privacy and take special efforts to maintain your trust. We offer a web site service that allows you to interact with other users; this document provides a thorough description of such tools and our practices to help you understand our approaches to privacy. You should carefully read this Privacy Statement (the "Policy"). If you have any questions about this Policy please see our Privacy Policy FAQ or contact customer support. 

This Policy applies only to information collected on the GearTrade.com web site and partner websites powered by GearTrade.com. It does not speak about our practices for information collected elsewhere or the practices of any third parties, including those who operate sites on our behalf and that display our branding. 

**Information**

GearTrade is the sole owner of the information collected on the above sites. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement. GearTrade collects information from our users at several different points on our websites. 

**Log Files**

We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our websites. Your IP address is used to gather broad demographic information. We also gather information about your web browser and about which website referred you to our page. We do this to help our development and to measure the success of our partnership and advertising programs. This information is not linked to personally identifiable information. 

**Sharing**

We will share aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person. We use a credit card processing company to bill users for goods and services. This company does not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes. 

**Cookies**

Cookies are pieces of information that a website transfers to your computer's hard disk for record-keeping purposes. Cookies can make the Web more useful by storing information about your preferences on a particular site. The use of Cookies is an industry standard, and most major websites use them to provide useful features for their customers. The GearTrade websites above use Cookies. Cookies in and of themselves do not personally identify users and usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our sites. Most browsers are initially set to accept Cookies. If you'd prefer, you can set yours to refuse Cookies. However, you will not be able to use any of the features of our website that require you to log in (buy gear, sell gear, login to My Account). Cookies can also enable GearTrade to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site. 

**Surveys & Contests**

From time-to-time our site requests information from users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and shipping address) and demographic information (such as zip code, age level, or income level). Contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes. Demographic information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site. 

**Personal Information**

We will explicitly ask when we need information that personally identifies you or allows us to contact you ("Personal Information"). This information is requested when registering to participate with GearTrade through any of the websites listed above. Our site's registration form requires users to give us contact information (like your name and email address) that we store in our database on our servers. We use your contact information to contact you when necessary and to contact the user about the services on our site for which they have expressed interest. We also collect financial information (like your account or credit card number) during the completed transaction process. Financial information that is collected is used to bill buyers and pay sellers for products and services. You will be able to access and change your Personal Information through My Account. You can visit My Account on any of the sites listed above to update and make changes to your GearTrade account and Personal Information. 

Personal Identifying Information is not shared with third parties. Any personally identifying information that we gather will only be used as far as needed because of your participation with GearTrade or with any of the websites listed above. 

**Reviewing and Changing Your Information**

We allow you the ability to review and change the personal information you provided to us at registration on your account page. You have the ability to add additional credit cards as well as select whether you wish to receive promotional mail from us. You agree to keep your information as current as possible and agree not to change your information to fake or fraudulent information. 

**Security of Your Information**

We make every effort and follow industry standard practices to safeguard the confidentiality of each user's personal information. All credit card information you submit is encrypted through secure server software (SSL). When you conduct a transaction on our site or when you log into your account, we encrypt all of your credit card information and store that information in our secure data center. All transactions are conducted through our secure servers, which are protected behind state-of-the-art firewalls. However, "absolute, 100%" security does not exist on the Internet and therefore you should not expect that your information will never be disclosed. 

**Password Control**

Except as specifically permitted by this section, you may not disclose your password to any third parties nor share it with any third parties. If you lose control of your password, you may lose substantial control over your personally identifiable information and may be subject to legally binding actions taken on your behalf. Therefore, if your password has been compromised for any reason, you should immediately change your password by editing your personal information in My Account. 

**Children (Minors)**

Children are not eligible to use our services and we ask that minors (under the age of 18) do not submit any personal information to us. If you are a minor, you can use this service only in conjunction with your parents or guardians. We are not responsible for minors who use their guardian's credit card on GearTrade or its associated partner websites. 

**Links**

This website contains links to other sites. We try to choose the sites we link to carefully, but please be aware that GearTrade is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. 

**Tell-A-Friend**

If a user elects to use our referral service for informing a friend about our site, we ask them for the friend's name and email address. GearTrade will automatically send the friend a one-time email inviting them to visit the site. GearTrade does not store this information. We only use it for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email. 

**Special Offers**

We send all new members a welcoming email to verify username. Established members will occasionally receive information on products, services, special deals, and a newsletter. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of communications. Please see our choice and opt-out below. 

**Special Relationships**

GearTrade has developed special relationships, such as "Powered By" partners, business partners, co-branded sites, and these relationships will be addressed here in the privacy statement when developed. Any information shared through these relationships will be of a non-personal character such as described in the information section above. We will not share any "Personal Information" with any of our special relationship partners. 

**Security**

This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. We have purchased and installed a digital certificate for the 'www.GearTrade.com' domain, and any sensitive financial information that we request during the order completion process will be protected by this certificate and by SSL encryption technology. We are also running the latest version of the Apache web server and Stronghold SSL, and all information stored in our system is encrypted at the file level in our database and is also protected from unauthorized outside users by our web server's firewall. 

**Third Party Advertising**

We use DoubleClick and other third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements on this site and other sites about goods and services that may be of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please click [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp). 

**Third Party Cookies**

In the course of serving advertisements to this site, our third-party advertiser may place or recognize a unique "cookie" on your browser. 

**Choice / Opt-Out**

Our site provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us at the point where we request information about the visitor. Simply uncheck the "Receive email From GearTrade" box when registering. You may also uncheck this box by visiting My Account from any of the above websites. To remove all of your information from our database, to not receive future communications, or to no longer receive our services, please email customer service and request that your login ID and related information be deleted from our system. 

**Correct / Update**

To correct or update any information related to your account, visit My Account of any of the websites listed above to change and modify your contact information. 

**Spam**

GearTrade does not tolerate spam. Therefore, without limiting the foregoing, you are not licensed to add any user, even a user who has purchased an item from you, to your mail list (email or physical mail) without their express consent after adequate disclosure. 

**Contacting the Website**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this website, you can contact customer service. 

Back to Contents
